[
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 35,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Julio",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A solemn bard.",
            "job": "I seek the true nature of things!",
            "heal": "Solemn.",
            "keyword1": "NATU",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "All things have a true nature!",
            "answer2": "Compassion derives itself from unending love!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know the true nature of all things?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou art a liar and a braggart.",
            "noanswer": "No mortal can."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shapero",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A druid.",
            "job": "I am looking for Julio.",
            "heal": "All right.",
            "keyword1": "JULI",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "He knows the true nature of compassion.",
            "answer2": "Seek out Julio and ask him of compassion!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou on the Quest of the Avatar?",
            "yesanswer": "Find the shrine of compassion east across 2 bridges!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a child",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small child",
            "job": "I am learning compassion.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "LEAR",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "The solution to ones problems often lies in solving others!",
            "answer2": "Never care so much for thyself that thou cannot care for others!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye the mantra of compassion?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Ask Cricket!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a child",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small child",
            "job": "I am learning compassion.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "LEAR",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "The solution to ones problems often lies in solving others!",
            "answer2": "Never care so much for thyself that thou cannot care for others!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye the mantra of compassion?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Ask Cricket!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a child",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small child",
            "job": "I am learning compassion.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "LEAR",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "The solution to ones problems often lies in solving others!",
            "answer2": "Never care so much for thyself that thou cannot care for others!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye the mantra of compassion?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Ask Cricket!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sprite",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A poor beggar.",
            "job": "I have no job so now I beg!",
            "heal": "I fear I shall die of starvation!",
            "keyword1": "STAR",
            "keyword2": "BEG ",
            "answer1": "I have not eaten in a week!",
            "answer2": "Please! Help me!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou help me?",
            "yesanswer": "In return I shall tell thee that Pepper knows of the rune!",
            "noanswer": "I shall starve to death!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shalimar",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tired shepherd",
            "job": "I watch over the children.",
            "heal": "Good.",
            "keyword1": "CHIL",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "It takes a good deal of compassion to deal with children!",
            "answer2": "Compassion strengthens the soul as knowledge tempers the mind!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Have any kids?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou dost know what I mean!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 30,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Mentor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise shepherd.",
            "job": "I escaped Magincia!",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "MAGI",
            "keyword2": "PRID",
            "answer1": "Pride was too great in Magincia!",
            "answer2": "The city was destroyed by daemons for its pride!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou proud?",
            "yesanswer": "That is not a virtue!",
            "noanswer": "Pride exists without truth, love, or courage!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A cheerful guard.",
            "job": "I am a guard of course!",
            "heal": "I am fully healed.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "We guards have a lot of compassion.",
            "answer2": "We always say: Let all others' troubles be as thine own!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou kill non-evil creatures?",
            "yesanswer": "That does not show compassion!",
            "noanswer": "Good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sebastian",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An injured person.",
            "job": "I know a terrible secret!",
            "heal": "Not so well.",
            "keyword1": "SECR",
            "keyword2": "MOND",
            "answer1": "Mondain's influence has not left the world!",
            "answer2": "An artifact remains! I heard at Buccaneer's Den!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou find and destroy it?",
            "yesanswer": "Then ask at the pub there of the skull!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A cheerful guard.",
            "job": "I am a guard of course!",
            "heal": "I am fully healed.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "We guards have a lot of compassion.",
            "answer2": "We always say: Let all others' troubles be as thine own!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou kill non-evil creatures?",
            "yesanswer": "That does not show compassion!",
            "noanswer": "Good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A cheerful guard.",
            "job": "I am a guard of course!",
            "heal": "I am fully healed.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "We guards have a lot of compassion.",
            "answer2": "We always say: Let all others' troubles be as thine own!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou kill non-evil creatures?",
            "yesanswer": "That does not show compassion!",
            "noanswer": "Good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Joe",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A drunken fighter",
            "job": "Yo ho ho... and a bottle... of rum... hic...",
            "heal": "And a bottle of...",
            "keyword1": "STON",
            "keyword2": "RUM ",
            "answer1": "The yellow stone is in the dungeon Despise...",
            "answer2": "Rum... hic...",
            "yesnoquestion": "Give me rum?...",
            "yesanswer": "Thanxth... my friend Joe can help with the stones... hic...",
            "noanswer": "Ah, be a joe!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Thevel",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A seasoned fighter.",
            "job": "I search for the mystery of the magic orbs.",
            "heal": "Fairly well.",
            "keyword1": "ORBS",
            "keyword2": "MAGI",
            "answer1": "A one-handed beggar knows their secrets!",
            "answer2": "Magic orbs.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou seen him?",
            "yesanswer": "Only he knows the orb's gift!",
            "noanswer": "Find him in Serpent castle for he knows of orbs!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Joe",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A drunken fighter",
            "job": "Yo ho ho... and a bottle... of rum... hic...",
            "heal": "And a bottle of...",
            "keyword1": "STON",
            "keyword2": "RUM ",
            "answer1": "The yellow stone is in the dungeon Despise...",
            "answer2": "Rum... hic...",
            "yesnoquestion": "Give me rum?...",
            "yesanswer": "Thanxth... my friend Joe can help with the stones... hic...",
            "noanswer": "Ah, be a joe!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 85,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Cricket",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A bard in green",
            "job": "Shhh, I'm playing!",
            "heal": "Shhh",
            "keyword1": "SHHH",
            "keyword2": "MANT",
            "answer1": "Yes, shhh!",
            "answer2": "The mantra for the shrine of compassion is 'MU'!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Now wilt thou be quiet?",
            "yesanswer": "Thanks.",
            "noanswer": "I am going to call the guards!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Joe",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A drunken fighter",
            "job": "Yo ho ho... and a bottle... of rum... hic...",
            "heal": "And a bottle of...",
            "keyword1": "STON",
            "keyword2": "RUM ",
            "answer1": "The yellow stone is in the dungeon Despise...",
            "answer2": "Rum... hic...",
            "yesnoquestion": "Give me rum?...",
            "yesanswer": "Thanxth... my friend Joe can help with the stones... hic...",
            "noanswer": "Ah, be a joe!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 35,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Pepper",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A spicy woman.",
            "job": "I am a fighting bard.",
            "heal": "Healthy.",
            "keyword1": "BARD",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "Bards know many things.",
            "answer2": "The rune of compassion lies at the end of a hall somewhere in this towne.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek something?",
            "yesanswer": "What might that be?",
            "noanswer": "Alas, I may have been able to help."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "I guard the bridge.",
            "heal": "Good.",
            "keyword1": "BRID",
            "keyword2": "GUAR",
            "answer1": "Across the bridge our people dance and sing!",
            "answer2": "Yep.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Would thou like to join them?",
            "yesanswer": "Remember, an open heart is the first step on the path to wisdom!",
            "noanswer": "Then you have no business across the bridge."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "I guard the bridge.",
            "heal": "Good.",
            "keyword1": "BRID",
            "keyword2": "GUAR",
            "answer1": "Across the bridge our people dance and sing!",
            "answer2": "Yep.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Would thou like to join them?",
            "yesanswer": "Remember, an open heart is the first step on the path to wisdom!",
            "noanswer": "Then you have no business across the bridge."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 86,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Gweno",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "a charming jester",
            "job": "I dance and sing for the children.",
            "heal": "Very well.",
            "keyword1": "DANC",
            "keyword2": "BEGG",
            "answer1": "Dance is good for the soul.",
            "answer2": "To give to a beggar shows compassion.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you give to the needy?",
            "yesanswer": "Beggars are thankful for small donations.",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a child",
            "pronoun": "The child",
            "look": "a small child",
            "job": "Singing",
            "heal": "Very happy.",
            "keyword1": "SING",
            "keyword2": "HO E",
            "answer1": "The song goes: Ho eyo he hum!",
            "answer2": "It means: Love to one and all!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you like the song?",
            "yesanswer": "Then help us spread the word!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a child",
            "pronoun": "The child",
            "look": "a small child",
            "job": "Singing",
            "heal": "Very happy.",
            "keyword1": "SING",
            "keyword2": "HO E",
            "answer1": "The song goes: Ho eyo he hum!",
            "answer2": "It means: Love to one and all!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you like the song?",
            "yesanswer": "Then help us spread the word!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 1,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "armourvendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "weaponvendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a child",
            "pronoun": "The child",
            "look": "a small child",
            "job": "Singing",
            "heal": "Very happy.",
            "keyword1": "SING",
            "keyword2": "HO E",
            "answer1": "The song goes: Ho eyo he hum!",
            "answer2": "It means: Love to one and all!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you like the song?",
            "yesanswer": "Then help us spread the word!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 30,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 84,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Iolo",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "Charming bard",
            "job": "I play for the people.",
            "heal": "Good.",
            "keyword1": "PLAY",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "I play my lute and receive the good wishes of the people.",
            "answer2": "If you treat someone else well then they will have reason to do the same.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you like my music?",
            "yesanswer": "I would join thee!",
            "noanswer": "A shame."
        }
    }
]
